Direct Action is a action, adventure, crime film directed by Sidney J. Furie.
Frank Gannon, a veteran cop, is being hunted by his fellow police officers after they learned he has
betrayed the brotherhood and exposed to the feds wide scale corruption of the LAPD.
He has one day left to prove his case and survive.
Frank Gannon, played by Dolph Lundgren.
Billie Ross, played by Polly Shannon.
Bryant, played by Donald Burda.
Ed Grimes, played by Rothaford Gray.
Captain Stone, played by Conrad Dunn.
Espinoza, played by Walter Alza.
Direct action is a form of activism in which participants use
economic power or political power to achieve their goals.
The aim of direct action is to either obstruct a certain practice such as a government's laws or
actions or to draw attention to and create a dialogue in order to solve perceived problems.
Direct action may include activities, that can be either violent or nonviolent, targeting people,
groups, institutions, actions, or property that its participants deem objectionable.
Violent direct action may include political violence,
assault, arson, sabotage, and property destruction.
Nonviolent direct action may include peaceful demonstrations, civil
disobedience, sit-ins, strikes, and counter-economics.
The tone is intense.